breitling.com 2019-06-30

# Privacy policy | Breitling

Last updated: February 2019

The protection of your personal data (see definition § 2 below) is important to Breitling. The present privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") describes the way Breitling processes your personal data.  This Privacy Policy applies to all entities of Breitling group, Breitling SA, its subsidiaries and its affiliated companies, its boutiques and its authorized retailers (“Breitling/ we/ us/ our”).

### 1\. General

1.1. Breitling, a Swiss-based company with registered seat at Schlachthausstrasse 2, 2540 Grenchen, Switzerland, is the controller (Controller) of all data collected in accordance with the current Privacy Policy. 

1.2. Hosting services for our website is provided by Infomaniak Network SA in Switzerland. Mobile applications may be hosted by us or by other companies.

### 2\. Personal Data

2.1. The term personal data used herein applies to all personal information relating to an identified or identifiable person ("Personal Data"). This includes information such as title, name, gender, address, date of birth, e-mail address, telephone number, mobile number, IP address, payment details, and other information like the pages you looked at, the purchases made on our website or through our Concierge Service, your preferences regarding our products  and your reactions to offers displayed on our online services, such as our website and mobile applications (collectively the "IT-Platforms ").

2.2 You can access to and browse on most areas of our IT-Platforms without having to provide personal details. However, the access to certain areas and functions of our IT-Platforms may require registration of certain Personal Data. By entering your Personal Data in the fields requested, you enable Breitling to provide you with the services you select.

### 3\. Data collection and processing

3.1. Your Personal Data may be collected by Breitling and, on its behalf, by its subsidiaries and its affiliated companies, its boutiques and its authorized retailers, the list of which is accessible on our website: www.breitling.com.

3.2. We may collect your Personal Data when you access our services, our IT-Platforms and when you call our Concierge Service. We may further collect them in our customer service centers, boutiques, points of sale and at Breitling’s events.

3.3. Breitling may authorize its subsidiaries and its affiliated companies, its boutiques and its authorized retailers, and third parties to process your Personal Data, on behalf of Breitling or for their own purposes, and will do so on the condition that they commit to offer the same level of protection for your Personal Data as we do.

### 4\. Use of your Personal Data

4.1. We collect your Personal Data to provide you information that you have requested from us, including information about us, our products, special offers, event invitations, our services, and our business partners, based on your consent or for other legal grounds, provided you have not objected to being contacted for these purposes. 

4.2. We also collect your Personal Data to manage and fulfil purchase orders directly or through our Concierge Service (e.g. to invoice our products, process your bank details, make refund, send you an order confirmation, deliver your products) and repair orders, to provide after service care and to deal with any other of your enquiries and requests.

4.3. We collect anonymized and statistical Data so that we can understand how our IT-Platforms and our customer services such as our Concierge Service are used, adapt and customize our IT-Platforms and our customer services for users, assist the use of the IT-Platforms, for market research and improve the IT-Platforms and the customer services generally.

4.4. We also collect your Personal Data to prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities and as part of our efforts to keep our IT-Platforms secure.

4.5. Please note that we expressly reserve the right to verify the accuracy of the Personal Data you submit, in particular with regard to contact details (postal address, email, phone, etc.), financial and bank information and the purchase of our products or use of our services.

### 5\. Retention of your Personal Data

5.1. We will keep your Personal Data no longer than the reasonable time necessary for the purposes as set out in this Privacy Policy and for satisfying any legal or regulatory requirements, and more particularly:

Personal Data processed for answering your request and providing you information about us, our products, special offers, event invitations, our services, and our business partners, will be kept for 2 year after your last contact with us or after the date you unsubscribe or object to such communication;

Personal Data processed for the good performance and management of our contractual relationship with you, will be kept for the necessary duration but no longer than 3 years after the end of your business relation with us or your last contact with us;

Personal Data collected to prevent fraud and other prohibited or illegal activities will be kept for the duration necessary for protecting ourselves in the event of a legal claim but no longer than 10 years from the last processing;

Data related to the history of your purchases, payments, the services provided to you, your service requests and/or complaints, will be kept for 10 years from the last event, unless we are required by law to retain the data for a longer duration;

Data processing records related to the management of your request for access to, rectification or deletion of your Personal Data, will be kept for the duration necessary for protecting ourselves in the event of a legal claim but no longer than 5 years from the last event.

5.2. The above data retention periods apply, unless we may be required by law, in specific circumstances, to retain the data for a longer duration.

5.3. In accordance to section 14 below, you have the right to ask for the deletion of your Personal Data at any time, to the extent compatible with legal obligation that may impose longer data retention periods on us.

5.4. At the end of these data retention periods, your Personal Data will be permanently deleted or fully anonymized.  

### 6\. Newsletter

6.1. You can conveniently subscribe to our Breitling Newsletter in the "Subscribe Newsletter" area. Simply enter your e-mail address in the field provided and the click on "OK". We will send a confirmation e-mail to the e-mail address you register.

6.2. If you no longer wish to receive news updates from Breitling, simply click on the "Unsubscribe" link that you find at the end of each newsletter.

### 7\. Cookies

 **Definition of cookies**

7.1. On our IT-Platforms, we use cookies. Cookies are small files that are saved on your computer or mobile device when you visit or use our IT-Platforms. Cookies save certain settings via your browser as well as data regarding information exchanged with the IT-Platforms via your browser.

7.2. Most of the cookies that we use are temporary, exist only while your browser is open and are deleted automatically once you close your browser. We also use permanent cookies which survive after your browser is closed, and can be used to recognize your computer or mobile device when you open your browser and browse the internet again. Depending on the type of permanent cookies, they remain on your computer or device for a certain period of time and are then automatically deactivated after the programmed period has expired.

 **Why do we use cookies?**

7.3. Cookies help us to make a number of functions on our IT-Platforms available. For example, cookies will enable the IT-Platforms to remember your preferences such as language or product preferences so that you do not have to keep re-entering them whenever you come back to the IT-Platforms or browse from one page to another.

7.4. By using cookies, we can also analyze how our visitors use our IT-Platforms, navigate and complete purchases on our website. This includes the number of visitors to our IT-Platforms, the platforms that referred them to our IT-Platforms and the pages that they visited on our IT-Platforms. This information enables us to create more user-friendly and effective IT-Platforms, to gather broad demographic information and to monitor the level of activity on our IT-Platforms.

7.5. Also, we use cookies for a more efficient use of advertising. Those cookies enable us to display advertising that presumably relates to your areas of interests based on the usage information we have collected from your visits to the IT-Platforms.

 **What kind of information is stored in cookies?**

7.6. Cookies capture usage information such as the date and time of your visit, the IP address of your device and the operating system you use. Additionally, cookies may store information with regard to the sites you came from before you arrived on our IT-Platforms. Also, cookies may allow us to track the topics you were researching on our IT-Platforms, which products you added in your shopping cart and what purchases you made on our IT Platforms.

7.7 Once a cookie is activated, it is given an ID number, which is used for internal reference and is not used to identify the user or access any personal information.

 **Cookies from third parties**

7.8. Cookies on our IT-Platforms may also be served by a third party service provider such as advertising partners.

7.9. These cookies help our partner companies to recognize your computer or mobile device when it visits other platforms. They will enable our partner companies to display advertising and other content that is tailored to your interests. These cookies will stay on your computer or device for a determined period and are then automatically deactivated after the programmed period has expired.

 **Managing your cookie preferences**

7.10. If you do not want to use cookies, you should consult your browser settings for information about your ability to delete saved cookies or object to the use of cookies. Many browsers can be configured so that cookies can be accepted with your permission or completely blocked. You may also be able to configure your browser settings so that they do not allow cookies to be accepted or saved at any time. Alternatively, you may be able to opt to be shown a warning message every time before you accept cookies or set your browser up in such a way that it only accepts cookies from certain websites.

7.11. If you do not want to use cookies, this will not prevent you from accessing the IT-Platforms. Please note, however, that if you decline cookies, you may not be able to see certain information on our IT-Platforms and some functions on the IT-Platforms may be limited or unavailable. 

7.12. You can also configure the opt-out setting of the cookies used on our websites via our Cookie Dashboard.

 **Which cookies do we use?**

1) Technical Cookie: Technical cookies help to make our website usable by enabling basic functions such as page navigation and access to secure areas of the website. The website cannot function properly without these cookies.

Name| Provider| Duration| Type  
---|---|---|---  
PHPSESSID| Breitling| Session| Technical cookie  
MOCKSESSID| Breitling| Session| Technical cookie  
AKAMAI_*| Akamai| Session| Technical cookie  
AKA_*| Akamai| Session| Technical cookie  
br_cookies_*| Breitling| 1 year| Technical cookie  
  
2) Statistics: Statistics cookies help website owners understand how visitors interact with websites by collecting and reporting information anonymously.

Name| Provider| Duration| Type  
---|---|---|---  
_ga| Google Analytics| 2 years| Statistics Cookie  
_gid| Google Analytics| 1 day| Statistics Cookie  
_gat_*| Google Analytics| 1 minute| Statistics Cookie  
__utma| Google Analytics| 2 years| Statistics Cookie  
__utmb| Google Analytics| 30 minutes| Statistics Cookie  
__utmc| Google Analytics| Session| Statistics Cookie  
__utmt| Google Analytics| 10 minutes| Statistics Cookie  
__utmz| Google Analytics| Session| Statistics Cookie  
  
3) Ads: Ads cookies are used to follow visitors to websites. The intention is to show ads that are relevant and appealing to individual users and are therefore more valuable to publishers and third party advertisers.

Name| Provider| Duration| Type  
---|---|---|---  
tr| Facebook| 180 days| Ads Cookie  
fr| Facebook| 180 days| Ads Cookie  
lang| Twitter| 180 days| Ads Cookie  
  
4) Social Media Cookies: These cookies are used to interact with social medias.

### 8\. Log Files

8.1. Whilst visiting our IT-Platforms, certain information is automatically sent from your browser to our server log files where it will be saved. This information relates to your activity on our IT-Platforms and includes: time and date of visit to our IT-Platform, which pages were viewed whilst on our IT-Platform, the selected products and/or the purchases made on our IT-Platform, your IP address, the URL of the website which linked you to our IT-Platform, how much information has been stored and which browser you have been using.

8.2. Once we have this information, the IP addresses are deleted or anonymized. The anonymous information stored in this log file is then used to improve your browsing experience by making our navigation more user-friendly, finding errors quickly and directing our server's capacity to where it is needed most.

### 9\. Sharing of Personal Data with Affiliated Companies and Third Parties

9.1. Without prejudice to the below Sections 9.2 to 9.5, we will only transfer your Personal Data to affiliated companies or to third parties if such recipient committed himself towards Breitling SA to observe the applicable data protection laws.

9.2. Likewise, we may transfer our databases containing your Personal Data in case all or a portion of Breitling's assets are acquired by one or more third parties as a result of a merger, sale, consolidation or liquidation.  

9.3. We may also pass your details to our agents and subcontractors to help us with any of our uses of your Personal Data set out in our Privacy Policy. For example, we may use third parties to complete and fulfill your orders, to assist us with delivering products to you, to finalize payment for ordered products or to help us collect payments from you, to analyze data and to provide us with marketing or customer service assistance.

9.4. In addition, we may also process your Personal Data and pass it to third parties where this is necessary or appropriate to comply with applicable legislation and/or regulations, check compliance therewith, prevent fraud, or respond to enquiries from responsible authorities.

9.5. Finally, we may share data in our possession in an anonymized form, which does not permit your identification (for example in the form of studies, reports or statistics).

### 10\. Web Analysis Tools

10.1. We may use web analysis tools, such as Google Analytics, for the purpose of evaluating how people use our IT-Platforms. Typically, these tools are provided by third parties. As a general rule, the information required for this analysis is captured by cookies and other tracking technologies on an anonymous basis and sent to a third-party server. Thus, depending where the server is located, the information may be sent abroad.

10.2. As mentioned above, you may refuse the use of cookies and therefore the use of web analysis tools by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser. You can also prevent your data (incl. IP address) from being used by Google Analytics by downloading and installing the Google Analytics browser add-on, which is available here.

### 11\. Social Plug-ins

11.1. Our IT-Platforms use so-called social plug-ins of social networks such as Facebook, Twitter, Youtube, Google+, Pinterest or Instagram. Those social plug-ins are identifiable by their social network logos on the IT-Platforms.

11.2. When you visit our IT-Platforms, these plug-ins are deactivated by default, i.e. without your intervention they will not send any data to third parties. The plug-ins are only activated if you click on the icons. They then remain active until you deactivate them again or delete your cookies.

11.3. When you visit a page of our IT-Platforms that has an activated plug-in, your browser will establish a direct connection to the server of the respective social network. The plug-in content will be directly transferred by the provider's server to your browser and integrated on the page you are visiting. For this purpose, the internet address of the visited site (your IP address included) may be transferred to servers based abroad where the data are stored. This will occur even if you do not have an account of the concerned social network or are not logged into it at the time.

11.4. If you are logged into the social network, your visit may be immediately linked to your social network account. If you interact with the plug-ins, for example by clicking "Like", or entering a comment, the corresponding information will also be transmitted directly from your browser to a server at third party and saved there. The information may also be published on the social network and shown to your contacts.

11.5. If you would like to prevent the social networks from linking your personal information concerning your visit to our IT-Platforms with the social networks in questions, please log out of that social network before entering our IT-Platforms. You may also be able to completely block plug-ins by using add-ons buttons for your browser, such as "Facebook Blocker", "NoScript" or "Ghostery".

11.6. For information on the purpose and extent of the data processing by the social network concerned, and about the rights and settings possibilities for the protection of your private sphere, please refer to the data protection information provided by the social network in question.

### 12\. Links to Third Party Websites

12.1. Certain activities through the IT-Platforms may be linked with those from other unrelated third-party companies that offer you the option to share your Personal Data with the third party. Links provided on the IT-Platforms to third party platforms are provided as a convenience to you and we do not control those platforms or their privacy practices, which may differ from ours. We do not endorse or make any representations about any third-party platforms that may be accessible through the IT-Platforms. We encourage you to review the privacy policy of any company before submitting your Personal Data. The Personal Data you choose to give to unrelated third parties is covered by their privacy policies, not this Privacy Policy. Some third-party companies may choose to share their personal data with us; that sharing is governed by that third party company's privacy policy.

### 13\. Security

13.1. Keeping your Personal Data secure is important to us. Whilst we are unable to guarantee 100% security, we will do our best and put in place measures in order not to allow your Personal Data to be accessed by unauthorized third parties. For these reasons, telephone conversations during the purchase of our products through our Concierge Service is likely to be recorded. Note that all information transmitted to our Concierge Service is encrypted.  

### 14\. Your Rights regarding your Personal Data

14.1. Under certain circumstances, data protection laws give you the following rights in relation to your Personal Data:

14.1.1. to obtain information about your Personal Data processed by us;

14.1.2. to obtain without undue delay the rectification of your Personal Data stored by us, or to have them completed;

14.1.3. to obtain the erasure of your Personal Data stored by us, unless the processing is necessary for exercising the right of freedom of expression or information, for compliance with a legal obligation, for reasons of public interest or for the establishment exercise or defense of legal claims. If we have made your Personal Data public, we are obliged, taking account of available technology and the technical possibilities, to inform controllers which are processing the Personal Data that you have requested the erasure by such controllers of any links to, or copy or replication of, those Personal Data;

14.1.4. to obtain the restriction of the processing of your Personal Data if you contest the accuracy of the Personal Data, the processing is unlawful, but you oppose their erasure and we no longer require the data, but you require these for the establishment, exercise or defense of legal claims or you have objected to their processing;

14.1.5. to receive your Personal Data in a structure, commonly used and machine-readable format or have such transmitted to another controller;

14.1.6. to withdraw your consent given to us at any time. This means that we may no longer continue the data processing based on this consent in future, being specified that any data processing based on another legal basis may remain possible;

14.1.7. to complain to a supervisory authority. You can usually contact the supervisory authority at your normal place of residence or your workplace or where we are headquartered or the place of any alleged infringement for this.

14.2. If your Personal Data are processed on the basis of legitimate interests, you have the right to object to the processing of your Personal Data if grounds for this relating to your particular situation exist or the objection is to direct marketing. In the latter case you have a general right to object, which is implemented by us without any particular situation being specified. Sending an e-mail to dataprivacy@breitling.com is sufficient if you wish to exercise your right to object.

14.3. Your request must be sent to the Controller in writing or by electronic form means, at the following address:

E-Mail: [dataprivacy@breitling.com](mailto:dataprivacy@breitling.com)

Address: Breitling SA, Schlachthausstrasse 2, 2540 Grenchen, Switzerland.

We reserve our right to ask for any further information or document in order to verify, when needed, your identity before processing a request you may have based on the above-mentioned rights.

### 15\. Modifications

15.1. Breitling reserves the right to modify this Privacy Policy at any time and at its sole discretion. The new dated version of the Privacy Policy takes effect as soon as it is published on our IT-Platforms. Please kindly note that it is your own responsibility to regularly review our Privacy Policy in order to stay informed about any modification thereto.

### CONTACT US

If you have any questions or comments about this Privacy Policy please contact us at the address provided below. You must also use this address if you wish to exercise your rights pursuant to Section 14 above.

E-Mail: [dataprivacy@breitling.com](mailto:dataprivacy@breitling.com)

Address: Breitling SA, Schlachthausstrasse 2, 2540 Grenchen, Switzerland
